

GERSHOM CHARIC

PRODUCT DESIGNER

CONTACTS

- (+39) 333 4386 964
- O Milan, Italy
- gershom.charig@gmail.com
- gershomcharig.com

PORTFOLIOS

BEHANCE

behance.net/gershomcharig

DRIBBBLE

dribbble.com/gershom

EDUCATION

PROFESSIONAL WEB DESIGN CERTIFICATE

Formater, 2008 - 2009

SCIENTIFIC HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

Liceo "L.B. Alberti", 2002 - 2007

LANGUAGES

ITALIAN

Native

ENGLISH

Professional working proficiency

EXPERTISE

- User Experience Design
- User Interface Design
- Branding
- · Art Direction
- Web Design
- Mobile App Design
- · Usability
- User Research
- Information Architecture
- · Data Analysis

PROFILE

I'm a product designer with 9+ years of experience in building digital products and brand identities, currently based in Milan, born in 1988. For the last 5 years I've been responsible for user experience and art direction of several fintech companies.

I specialize in financial products and services, both B2C and B2B. My goal is to help people and businesses to achieve more through my work.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT DESIGNER at Credimi

09/2015 - Present

Company's first employee and member of the management team. Responsible for product design, customer experience and brand identity.

- Designed the user experience and the interface of the product B2B.
- Designed the brand identity of the company and the advertising assets.
- Helped the company become the fastest-growing digital lending platform in Europe, UK included, thanks to €80M funded to SMEs within it's first year of activity.
- Leading a small design team since 2018.
- Helped the company get a €10M series-A funding round

PRODUCT DESIGNER at Objectway

06/2015 - 09/2015

PRODUCT DESIGNER at MoneyFarm

10/2012 - 06/2015

The only designer of the company for the entire period of collaboration. Responsible for product design, customer experience, brand identity and advertising.

- Designed the user experience and the interface of the product, for the web and for the mobile native app B2C.
- Designed the brand identity of the company and the advertising assets.
- Improved conversion rates by 46% through user testing and usercentered design.
- 30K+ users, 2K+ paying customers, €150M+ AUM, certified 97% customer satisfaction rate.
- Helped the company get a €16M series-A funding round and FCA authorization in UK.

As a company side-project I also designed BudJet, a mobile app for tracking expenses and incomes.

- 40K+ downloads in Italy.
- Ranked in the top 5 'Finance' apps on App Store.

GRAPHIC DESIGNER at Adverteaser

06/2009 - 10/2012

Worked with some top-class Italian and international companies such as Nestlé, GE, Schneider Electric, Coty, Unilever, Calvin Klein, Carrefour and Lancaster.